

VINH CHAU

♦ Phone: (+84) 765 808 290 **■ Email:** chauvinhtth13@gmail.com

Skype: live:chauvinhtth13

in Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/vinhchau-4bb06b85

Github: github.com/chauvinhtth13

ORCID: orcid.org/0000-0001-6634-7267

Google Scholar: scholar.google.com/citations?user=8DSaPmwAAAAJ

About Me

I hold a Bachelor's degree in Mathematics and a Master's in Computer Science from the University of Science at Vietnam National University in Ho Chi Minh City. My academic background has equipped me with a strong foundation in quantitative analysis, problem-solving, and computational techniques. Additionally, I have pursued coursework in public health and epidemiology, furthering my understanding of addressing complex healthcare challenges. My unwavering dedication to advancing knowledge at the intersection of computer science, public health, and epidemiology positions me to contribute significantly to research in these fields.

Work Experience

01/2022 - Current

Research Assistant

Molecular Epidemiology Group

Oxford University Clinical Research Unit - Ho Chi Minh City, Viet Nam

- Managed research data quality, ensuring the accuracy of studies.
- Developed and executed statistical analysis plans to support studies.
- Contributed to presentations, grant writing, and manuscript preparation.
- Supervised students on advanced R programming and clinical statistics.
- Provided technical support across diverse research projects.

10/2017 - 12/2021

Data Coordinator

Enteric Infection Group

Oxford University Clinical Research Unit - Ho Chi Minh City, Viet Nam

- Led and coordinated clinical research projects.
- Ensure data quality and accuracy throughout the clinical trial studies.
- Coordinate site visits for data monitoring and verification.
- Conducted statistical and geographic analyses to support studies.
- Designed and implemented monitoring systems for clinical trial research.
- Train research staff on data collection procedures and data entry systems.
- Manage vaccine storage conditions for the studies.

05/2015 - 08/2017

Mathematics Teacher Assistant

Faculty of Mathematics

Titan Education Center - Ho Chi Minh City, Viet Nam

- Lesson plan preparation assistance.
- Classroom material setup.
- Individual student support for learning challenges.
- Teacher's task assistance, such as grading and parent communication
- Student adjustment, learning, and socialization support.

Education

11/2017 - 11/2019

Master of Science in Computer Science

Faculty of Information Technology

University of Science, Vietnam National University - Ho Chi Minh City, Viet Nam

• Supervisors: Prof. Stephen Baker and Dr Le Thi Nhan

• Thesis Title: Feature selection methods for efficient Rotavirus diagnosis

• **GPA:** 3.22/4

• Thesis Grade: 3.5/4

08/2013 - 08/2017

Bachelor of Science in Mathematics

Faculty of Mathematics and Computer Science

University of Science, Vietnam National University - Ho Chi Minh City, Viet Nam

• Supervisors: Assoc. Prof. Pham The Bao

• Thesis Title: A deep learning approach for predicting protein binding sites

• **GPA:** 3.33/4.00

• Thesis Grade: 4.00/4.00

Cerftificates

Coursera - Google Learning Program/Vietnam National Innovation Center https://coursera.org/verify/specialization/3V6M6WEY3HJ2

02/2024 **Google IT Support**

Coursera - Google Learning Program/Vietnam National Innovation Center https://coursera.org/verify/specialization/R49P7L9Y8LDP

Coursera - Google Learning Program/Vietnam National Innovation Center https://coursera.org/verify/specialization/J8WBCPQQEN5M

03/2023 **Epidemiology for Public Health**

Coursera - Imperial College London https://coursera.org/verify/specialization/PX8G6TP2VT7D

09/2022 **Genome Information 2022**

Wellcome Connecting Science

10/2021 Medical Statistics

Stanford Online, Stanford Center for Professional Development

09/2020 **Vaccine Safety Basics**

Pasteur Institute of Ho Chi Minh City

No. 3021/B08-PAS

Hospital of Tropical Diseases - Ho Chi Minh city, Viet Nam

No. 29/2019/GCN-BVBNĐ

08/2016 Microsoft Office Specialist - Office Excel 2010

IIG Viet Nam

Identification Code: Pz2K-uGFu

Language Skills

Mother tongue(s):

Vietnamese

Other language(s): **English:** IELTS Overall 5.5

Reading: 6.5Listening: 6Writing: 4.5Speaking: 5.0

Other Skills

Coding Python, R, C/C++, Matlab, 上TEX, Kotlin, Visual Basic.

Databases SQL Server, MySQL, Microsoft Access.

Data Analysis □ Orange, Tableau, R, Microsoft Power-Bl

Design Proficient in Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Audition, Coredraw

Office Advanced user of Google Workspace and Microsoft Office.

Research Publications

Journal Articles

- H. T. T. Nguyen, **V. Chau**, P. H. L. Nguyen, H. D. Du, L. N. P. Nguyen, T. Q. N. Le, P. T. Huynh, T. N. T. Nguyen, T. N. D. Tran, V. P. Voong, T. T. Ha, P. N. Q. Nguyen, S. Baker, G. Thwaites, M. Rabaa, and D. T. Pham, "Changing epidemiology and antimicrobial susceptibility of bloodstream infections at a vietnamese infectious diseases hospital (2010–2020)," *npj Antimicrobials and Resistance*, vol. 2, Oct. 2024, ISSN: 2731-8745. DOI: https://doi.org/10.1038/s44259-024-00049-0.
- Q. Nguyen, Y. T. P. Nguyen, T. T. Ha, D. T. N. Tran, P. V. Voong, **V. Chau**, P. L. N. Nguyen, N. T. Q. Le, L. P. H. Nguyen, T. T. N. Nguyen, T. V. Trinh, J. J. Carrique-Mas, S. Baker, G. Thwaites, M. A. Rabaa, M. Choisy, H. T. Chung, and D. T. Pham, "Genomic insights unveil the plasmid transfer mechanism and epidemiology of hypervirulent klebsiella pneumoniae in vietnam," *Nature Communications*, vol. 15, no. 1, p. 4187, May 2024. DOI: 10.1038/s41467-024-48206-3.
- N. H. M. Truong, Q. Nguyen, P. V. Voong, **V. Chau**, N. H. T. Nguyen, T. H. M. Nguyen, P. H. Vo, L. T. Nguyen, T. T. P. Ha, L. P. H. Nguyen, P. H. Le, D. P. Thanh, and H. D. Nguyen, "Genomic characterization of aeromonas spp. isolates from striped catfish with motile aeromonas septicemia and human bloodstream infections in vietnam," *Microbial Genomics*, vol. 10, no. 5, May 2024, ISSN: 2057-5858. DOI: 10.1099/mgen.0.001248.
- T. T. N. Dung, P. V. Vinh, **V. Chau**, N. P. H. Lan, N. L. N. Phuong, L. T. Q. Ngan, G. Thwaites, L. Thwaites, M. Rabaa, A. T. Nguyen, *et al.*, "Development and validation of multiplex real-time pcr for simultaneous detection of six bacterial pathogens causing lower respiratory tract infections and antimicrobial resistance genes," *BMC Infectious Diseases*, vol. 24, no. 1, p. 164, Feb. 2024. DOI: 10.1186/s12879-024-09028-2.
- T. T. Quỳnh, H. P. Thảo, H. M. Phương, **C. Vinh**, L. T. M. Vân, N. P. T. Nhiên, N. V. V. Châu, and N. T. H. Yến, "Đánh giá chi phí hiệu quả của vancomycin trước và sau khi áp dụng kỹ thuật theo dõi nồng độ thuốc trong máu bằng thông số auc mục tiêu tại bệnh viện bệnh nhiệt đới thành phố hồ chí minh giai đoạn 2020-2021," *Tạp chí Y học Việt Nam*, vol. 534, Jan. 2024, ISSN: 1859-1868. DOI: 0.51298/vmj.v534i1b.8273.

- D. T. H. Diep, H. M. Tuan, K. M. Ngoc, **C. Vinh**, T. T. N. Dung, V. V. Phat, Q. Nguyen, D. T. H. Tam, L. V. Nien, B. T. H. Duyen, C. T. Phung, N. H. Bac, T. D. Tuan, G. Thwaites, M. A. Rabaa, and D. T. Pham, "The clinical features and genomic epidemiology of carbapenem-resistant acinetobacter baumannii infections at a tertiary hospital in vietnam," *Journal of Global Antimicrobial Resistance*, vol. 33, pp. 267–275, Apr. 2023, ISSN: 2213-7165. DOI: 10.1016/j.jgar.2023.04.007.
- N. Quynh, N. T. T. Nguyen, P. Phuong, **C. Vinh**, N. L. P. Huong, N. T. Duc, H. T. Thanh, L. N. T. Quynh, V. D. Thuy, B. Stephen, T. G. E., R. M. A., and P. D. Thanh, "Genomic insights into the circulation of pandemic fluoroquinolone-resistant extra-intestinal pathogenic Escherichia coli ST1193 in vietnam," *Microbial Genomics*, vol. 7, no. 12, Dec. 2021, ISSN: 2057-5858. DOI: 10.1099/mgen.0.000733.
- R. de Alwis, T. M. Phuc, B. Y. H. Bai, N. L. T. Quynh, P. T. T. Tam, T. T. N. Dung, N. T. T. Nhan, **C. Vinh**, H. V. Hien, L. T. H. Nhat, N. T. T. Hong, N. T. M. Tuyen, H. T. T. Trang, L. P. Thao, V. T. N. Diep, P. T. H. Chau, L. Q. Thinh, H. T. N. Thu, N. N. Hang, M. C. Danh, T. D. Hao, T. A. Dao, L. Dai, V. T. H. Diu, N. T. En, N. T. T. Hanh, L. T. Hanh, H. P. T. Hien, N. T. T. Linh, T. C. Darton, G. E. Thwaites, E. Kestelyn, L. L. Vi, B. T. T. Tien, H. T. D. Tuyet, C. Anderson, and S. Baker, "The influence of human genetic variation on early transcriptional responses and protective immunity following immunization with rotarix vaccine in infants in ho chi minh city in vietnam: A study protocol for an open single-arm interventional trial," *Wellcome Open Research*, vol. 5, Oct. 2020. DOI: 10.12688/wellcomeopenres.16090.1.
- T. P. Quang, R. M. A, L. D. Huy, T. D. Quang, Q. T. Dai, Q. H. Linh, H. T. N. Anh, D. P. Cong, N. N. Duy, T. T. Anh, Q. L. Ngoc, P. T. My, **C. Vinh**, K. N. Cong, A. D. Duc, D. T. Nhu, T. Guy, van Doorn H Rogier, C. Marc, and O. C.-1. R. Group, "The first 100 days of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (sars-cov-2) control in vietnam," *Clinical Infectious Diseases*, vol. 72, no. 9, e334–e342, Aug. 2020, ISSN: 1058-4838. DOI: 10.1093/cid/ciaa1130.

Conference Proceedings

V. Chau, D. T. Thi Ngoc, P. T. My, P. Duy, B. Stephen, R. Maia, and T. N. Le, "Feature selection methods for effective diagnosis of rotavirus infection: A comparative evaluation," in *15th International Conference on Knowledge and Systems Engineering, KSE2023, Hanoi, Vietnam, October 18-20, 2023*, IEEE, Oct. 2023, pp. 1–6. DOI: 10.1109/KSE59128.2023.10299472.

Honours and Awards

04/2021 OUCRU PE Seed Award

- Institution: Oxford University Clinical Research Unit Ho Chi Minh City, Viet Nam
- **Project Title:** Fostering clinical research procedure and barrier understanding through an interactive board game
- Role: Principal Investigator
- Prize Amount: \$5,500
- **Link:** https://www.oucru.org/project/fostering-an-understanding-of-clinical-research-though-an-original-interactive-board-game/

Honours and Awards (continued)

10/2019 **IoT Startup 2019**

• Institution: Saigon Hi-tech Park Incubation Center - Ho Chi Minh City, Viet Nam

 Project Title: OmniGo: Ecosystem expands the connection between users and daily transaction locations

• Role: Co-Founder

• Placement: First place

• **Link:** https://dost.hochiminhcity.gov.vn/hoat-dong-so-khcn/chung-ket-iot-startup-2019-giai-quyet-cac-nhu-cau-cu-doanh-nghiep-va-xa-hoi/

References

Dr. Pham Thanh Duy

Head of Molecular Epidemiology Group Centre for Tropical Medicine Oxford University Clinical Research Unit 764 Vo Van Kiet, Ward 1, District 5, Ho Chi Minh City, Viet Nam

■ duypt@oucru.org

Dr. Chung The Hao

Postdoctoral Researcher of Molecular Epidemiology Group
Centre for Tropical Medicine
Oxford University Clinical Research Unit
764 Vo Van Kiet, Ward 1, District 5, Ho Chi Minh City, Viet Nam

haoct@oucru.org

Dr. Le Thi Nhan

Faculty of Information Technology
University of Science, Vietnam National University - Ho Chi Minh City
227 Nguyen Van Cu Street, Ward 4, District 5, Ho Chi Minh City
Itnhan@fit.hcmus.edu.vn

Assoc. Prof. Pham The Bao

Dean of Faculty of Information Technology
Sai Gon University, Ho Chi Minh City
273 An Duong Vuong Street, Ward 3, District 5, Ho Chi Minh City

ptbao@sgu.edu.vn